## Romeu Fialho

Email: romeubaptistafialho.dev@gmail.com, Phone: 967092983, Portfolio: romeufialho.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Gameplay Programmer experienced with C#, C++ and cooperating with designers and artists to create gameplay features and mechanics in Unity or Unreal Engine. Previously studied base programming languages like C as well as Operative Systems, Computer Hardware, and Web Development.

#### **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

- Skills in C#, C++, OOP languages.
- Experience working with Unity and Unreal Engine.
- Over 2 years of experience working with and around video games.
- Worked with 3 small teams to create indie experiences.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### **GAME PROGRAMMER, FREELANCE**

March 2020 - Present Day

- Developing indie games and experiences using Unity and Unreal Engine.
- Keen to working as a team.

### **GAME PROGRAMMER, MONSOON GAMES**

February 2022 – September 2022

- Developed Gulp, a point and click simulator, using Unreal Engine 4.
- Responsible for all programming related tasks such as:
  - Creating the management systems that support day cycles, global and individual scores, dynamic request generation, etc.
  - Dealing with object physics and restricting their behaviours.
  - o Implementation of UI and sounds to support game features.

#### **GAME PROGRAMMER, WITCH CAT GAMES**

February 2021 – July 2021

- Developed Lyzzy, a 2D platformer, using Unity.
- Responsible for all Programming related tasks and implementation of animations, UI and sound

### **GAME DEVELOPER, SNAKE MARMALADE STUDIOS**

November 2020 - January 2021

- Developed Marmalade Thief, using GB Studio.
- Helped with Programming, Level Design and story-line.

### **EDUCATION**

# BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN GAMES AND MULTIMEDIA – INSTITUTO POLITÉCNICO DE LEIRIA – PORTUGAL

- Focused on C# and C++ programming.
- Game development in Unity and, especially, Unreal Engine.
- Game Design and documentation writing.
- Marketing & Business.

# OTHER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Accustomed to working with developing games in small teams and tight deadlines.